JAIVEER SINGH

6B/6 Uttri Marg,Old Rajinder Nagar, Mobile: +919811319020

New Delhi, India, 110060 Email: <u>luthra.jaiveer@gmail.com</u>

Profile

A Mechanical Engineer graduate who is enthusiastic, disciplined and an adaptable worker with a willingness and ability to excel within new encounters. An excellent communicator and team worker who enjoys problem solving with experience in managing successful group projects.

Education and Qualifications:

2012 - 2015 Bachelor of Engineering (BEng Honours) in Mechanical Engineering :

University of Southampton, U.K - Degree result: 2:2

Computing Skills MS Office, AutoCAD, Solid works

Work experience:

Kanwal Industrial Corporation (India) (January 2016 - present):

- Responsible for all sales and marketing operations of Easyflex-Zip Clip Wire Rope Suspension Systems - including client meetings, quotation generation, generating sales through cold calling, industry exhibitions, weekly blogs for website as well following up on directly received enquiries.
- Responsible for Sales through listing of products on multiple online portals such as Amazon, India Mart and SearchO, as well as following up on International enquiries received.
- Responsible for engineering tasks such as Cost Estimation, Selection of Products, Engineering Calculations, Seismic Designing and CAD Drawings for Wire Rope Systems, Vibration Isolators, Seismic Isolators and Pipe Supports.
- Responsible for Maintenance and regular evaluation of a complete list of enquiries based on their current status to ensure complete follow up and no loss in potential sales.
- Responsible for shifting production to the new manufacturing unit Ensuring smoothness and efficiency in production at every step
- Implemented production quality measures, safety policy and efficient stock management measures.
- Launched new product range of Exhaust & Ventilation System and responsible for all sales and marketing operations for the same. (https://www.amazon.in/Pax-Norte-Intelligent-Exhaust-White/dp/B01BHQ6TNM/ref=sr_1_1?ie=UTF8&qid=1482307535&sr=8-1&keywords=pax+norte)
- Responsible for SEO of the company website through weekly blogs, case studies as well as regular social media updates.
- Redesigned and rebranded Company Corporate Presentation, Corporate Video and Website.
- Initially managed shop floor to get a better understanding of manufacturing processes involved in production of all types of products - Expansion Bellows, Vibration Isolators, Seismic Isolators, Pipe Supports.

Bike Rack Company (UK) (June 2015 - October 2015):

- Responsible for Sales through Amazon, cold calling as well as generating leads through market research.
- Performed market research and feasibility study before launch of new product range.
- · Identified and implemented new business development strategy.
- Responsible for all marketing operations related to The Cycle Show at the NEC, Birmingham.
- · Defined and implemented online marketing strategy.
- Created and rolled out social media advertising through regular blogs, latest industry news as well as website SEO.
- Identified and researched potential suppliers of relevant products.

Achievements and Skills:

- Winner of Eurobot UK final in 2014 held at Middlesex University. Eurobot is an international robotics competition.
- Travelled to Dresden, Germany in June 2014 to participate in Eurobot World Finals, achieved top 30 place in the world competition
- Member of the Institute of Mechanical Engineers (IMechE).
- Excellent ability to juggle multiple tasks and projects and ensure timely execution.
- Regular attendance of industry seminars to keep track of industry insights and maintain industry relationships